<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Azure DevOps on Chendrayan Venkatesan</title>
    <link>/tags/azure-devops/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Azure DevOps on Chendrayan Venkatesan</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 25 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/azure-devops/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Create Azure DevOps Service Connection with Certificate using REST API</title>
      <link>/blog/create-service-connection-with-certificate-using-rest-api/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/create-service-connection-with-certificate-using-rest-api/</guid>
      <description>Introduction I have no access to my organization DevOps due to unfortunate technical issues, but that didn’t stop me from working. This morning I was on a call with a business owner who asked me to show the steps to create service connections with the certificate. Yes, I have to use the OPEN SSL tool to convert the PFX to PEM, and it was a bit difficult for me to walk him through the steps remotely.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DEPLOYING AZURE FUNCTION APP - EXTERNAL GIT</title>
      <link>/blog/deploying-azure-function-app-external-git/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/deploying-azure-function-app-external-git/</guid>
      <description>Introduction I bet most of you don’t need this! Having said that, if your organization has Azure DevOps (Formerly VSTS) in directory A and Azure on directory B. Then, deploying Azure Function App using external git may help you.
Why not Zip deploy? Yes, that’s the optimal way to do! In my case, the roller coaster ride for simple requirements is quite common. Consider, Azure Functions source code is available with vendors, and it’s an end to end solution to be deployed at your workplace in a shorter time, and building a pipeline may take a few hours or process may delay the deployment.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>