<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog on Chendrayan Venkatesan</title>
    <link>/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog on Chendrayan Venkatesan</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 03 Jan 2021 16:01:50 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Get Started with Project Bicep</title>
      <link>/blog/get-started-with-project-bicep/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Jan 2021 16:01:50 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/get-started-with-project-bicep/</guid>
      <description>References Refer to the below links to know more about the project bicep
 GitHub  Repository Docs Examples Tutorials Specifications    Introduction As a first step, we need to install the bicep tools on our local computer. If you need to deploy the solution using Az DevOps, follow the steps given in the &amp;ldquo;Deploy Bicep Solution using Azure DevOps&amp;rdquo; section.
Install Bicep $installPath = &amp;#34;$env:USERPROFILE\.bicep&amp;#34; $installDir = New-Item -ItemType Directory -Path $installPath -Force $installDir.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Logging Service Now Requests using Event Grid Trigger</title>
      <link>/blog/logging-service-now-requests-using-event-grid-trigger/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/logging-service-now-requests-using-event-grid-trigger/</guid>
      <description>Introduction A colleague of mine asked a solution for raising a service request in SNOW (Service Now) for each NSG rule creation and deletion. I requested to develop a service now catalog and allow the system to work with NSG. That means, from SNOW to Azure connectivity through REST API. However, the ask is the other way around. If a user creates/deletes the NSG rule in the portal, log a REQ with the minimum information</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Azure Devops Pipeline To Send Files Through Email With No Marketplace Extension</title>
      <link>/blog/azure-devops-pipeline-to-send-files-through-email-with-no-marketplace-extension/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/azure-devops-pipeline-to-send-files-through-email-with-no-marketplace-extension/</guid>
      <description>Introduction I was developing a PowerShell script to send Azure inventory through email, which generates a Word output with charts and tables. So, I thought of using Open XML, I used for SharePoint document library reporting (A few years ago), I searched GitHub and found a great PowerShell module PSWriteWord, and docs are super cool. Yes, this blog post is to show you the simple steps to generate a word document through Azure DevOps pipeline.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MY FIRST EXPERIENCE WITH THE AZURE DURABLE FUNCTIONS</title>
      <link>/blog/my-first-experience-with-the-azure-durable-functions/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/my-first-experience-with-the-azure-durable-functions/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Of late, I got a requirement to start the Azure runbooks programmatically (start a runbook through another runbook), and as a PowerShell fan, I said, “Start-AzAutomationAccountRunBook” is one best way to achieve it. An hour later, I got a call to build a script that waits until the job completes and gets the output. Here is a quick way “-Wait” parameter. Solved the issue? Yes! Now, it’s time for us to deliver a REST API endpoint, which is required to invoke in an Azure Pipeline for the business process.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Retrieve unattached Azure VM disks using PowerShell &amp; Azure Resource Graph</title>
      <link>/blog/retrieve-unattached-azure-vm-disks-using-powershell-azure-resource-graph/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/retrieve-unattached-azure-vm-disks-using-powershell-azure-resource-graph/</guid>
      <description>Introduction As part of the cost saving project task, I developed a PowerShell script to retrieve UNATTACHED disks. I used JOIN operator in this code to get a few tag information from the respective resource group.
 Replace value for the {TAGNAME}.
 $Query = &amp;#34;Resources | where type =~ &amp;#39;Microsoft.Compute/disks&amp;#39; | where properties.diskState =~ &amp;#39;Unattached&amp;#39; | project id, name, subscriptionId, resourceGroup, diskInGB = properties.diskSizeGB, diskState = properties.diskState, timeCreated = properties.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Create Azure DevOps Service Connection with Certificate using REST API</title>
      <link>/blog/create-service-connection-with-certificate-using-rest-api/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/create-service-connection-with-certificate-using-rest-api/</guid>
      <description>Introduction I have no access to my organization DevOps due to unfortunate technical issues, but that didn’t stop me from working. This morning I was on a call with a business owner who asked me to show the steps to create service connections with the certificate. Yes, I have to use the OPEN SSL tool to convert the PFX to PEM, and it was a bit difficult for me to walk him through the steps remotely.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Azure DevOps REST API helped me during outage of the VPN?</title>
      <link>/blog/how-azure-devops-rest-api-helped-me-during-outage-of-the-vpn/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/how-azure-devops-rest-api-helped-me-during-outage-of-the-vpn/</guid>
      <description>Introduction There is always an alternative is the apt statement to start this blog post! Yes, I got trouble in VPN and lost connection to most of our internal portal, and one among that is Azure DevOps (Formerly VSTS), where the code resides. Positively, no hindrances in accessing Outlook and Teams over mobile. All I need is to continue the work on code, work items and send status report.
 REST API is the savior!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DEPLOYING AZURE FUNCTION APP - EXTERNAL GIT</title>
      <link>/blog/deploying-azure-function-app-external-git/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/deploying-azure-function-app-external-git/</guid>
      <description>Introduction I bet most of you don’t need this! Having said that, if your organization has Azure DevOps (Formerly VSTS) in directory A and Azure on directory B. Then, deploying Azure Function App using external git may help you.
Why not Zip deploy? Yes, that’s the optimal way to do! In my case, the roller coaster ride for simple requirements is quite common. Consider, Azure Functions source code is available with vendors, and it’s an end to end solution to be deployed at your workplace in a shorter time, and building a pipeline may take a few hours or process may delay the deployment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating a New Theme</title>
      <link>/blog/creating-a-new-theme/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Sep 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/creating-a-new-theme/</guid>
      <description>Introduction This tutorial will show you how to create a simple theme in Hugo. I assume that you are familiar with HTML, the bash command line, and that you are comfortable using Markdown to format content. I&amp;rsquo;ll explain how Hugo uses templates and how you can organize your templates to create a theme. I won&amp;rsquo;t cover using CSS to style your theme.
We&amp;rsquo;ll start with creating a new site with a very basic template.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>(Hu)go Template Primer</title>
      <link>/blog/goisforlovers/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/goisforlovers/</guid>
      <description>Hugo uses the excellent go html/template library for its template engine. It is an extremely lightweight engine that provides a very small amount of logic. In our experience that it is just the right amount of logic to be able to create a good static website. If you have used other template systems from different languages or frameworks you will find a lot of similarities in go templates.
This document is a brief primer on using go templates.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Started with Hugo</title>
      <link>/blog/hugoisforlovers/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/hugoisforlovers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;step-1-install-hugo&#34;&gt;Step 1. Install Hugo&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Go to &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/spf13/hugo/releases&#34;&gt;hugo releases&lt;/a&gt; and download the
appropriate version for your os and architecture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Save it somewhere specific as we will be using it in the next step.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More complete instructions are available at &lt;a href=&#34;/overview/installing/&#34;&gt;installing hugo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Migrate to Hugo from Jekyll</title>
      <link>/blog/migrate-from-jekyll/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/migrate-from-jekyll/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;move-static-content-to-static&#34;&gt;Move static content to &lt;code&gt;static&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jekyll has a rule that any directory not starting with &lt;code&gt;_&lt;/code&gt; will be copied as-is to the &lt;code&gt;_site&lt;/code&gt; output. Hugo keeps all static content under &lt;code&gt;static&lt;/code&gt;. You should therefore move it all there.
With Jekyll, something that looked like&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;▾ &amp;lt;root&amp;gt;/
    ▾ images/
        logo.png
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>