<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>PowerShell on Chendrayan Venkatesan</title>
    <link>/tags/powershell/</link>
    <description>Recent content in PowerShell on Chendrayan Venkatesan</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 18 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/powershell/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>AZURE-DEVOPS-GENERATE-DOCX-SEND-EMAIL-WITH-NO-MARKETPLACE-EXTENSIONS</title>
      <link>/blog/azure-devops-generate-docx-send-email-with-no-marketplace-extensions.md/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/azure-devops-generate-docx-send-email-with-no-marketplace-extensions.md/</guid>
      <description>Introduction I was developing an as-built script for Azure infrastructure, which should produce a docx file output with charts and tables (especially for inventory). So, I thought of using Open XML, which I used, a few years ago for SharePoint document library reporting. I searched GitHub and found a great PowerShell module PSWriteWord, and docs are super cool. Yes, this blog post is to show you the simple steps to generate a word document through the Azure DevOps pipeline.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Retrieve unattached Azure VM disks using PowerShell &amp; Azure Resource Graph</title>
      <link>/blog/retrieve-unattached-azure-vm-disks/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/retrieve-unattached-azure-vm-disks/</guid>
      <description>Introduction As part of the cost saving project task, I developed a PowerShell script to retrieve UNATTACHED disks. I used JOIN operator in this code to get a few tag information from the respective resource group.
 Replace value for the {TAGNAME}.
 $Query = &amp;#34;Resources| where type =~ &amp;#39;Microsoft.Compute/disks&amp;#39;| where properties.diskState =~ &amp;#39;Unattached&amp;#39;| project id, name, subscriptionId, resourceGroup, diskInGB = properties.diskSizeGB, diskState = properties.diskState, timeCreated = properties.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Create Azure DevOps Service Connection with Certificate using REST API</title>
      <link>/blog/create-service-connection-with-certificate-using-rest-api/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/create-service-connection-with-certificate-using-rest-api/</guid>
      <description>Introduction I have no access to my organization DevOps due to unfortunate technical issues, but that didn’t stop me from working. This morning I was on a call with a business owner who asked me to show the steps to create service connections with the certificate. Yes, I have to use the OPEN SSL tool to convert the PFX to PEM, and it was a bit difficult for me to walk him through the steps remotely.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Azure DevOps REST API helped me during outage of the VPN?</title>
      <link>/blog/how-azure-devops-rest-api-helped-me-during-outage-of-the-vpn/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/how-azure-devops-rest-api-helped-me-during-outage-of-the-vpn/</guid>
      <description>Introduction There is always an alternative is the apt statement to start this blog post! Yes, I got trouble in VPN and lost connection to most of our internal portal, and one among that is Azure DevOps (Formerly VSTS), where the code resides. Positively, no hindrances in accessing Outlook and Teams over mobile. All I need is to continue the work on code, work items and send status report.
 REST API is the savior!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Azure Resource Graph Query - KQL Joins</title>
      <link>/blog/azure-resource-graph-query-kql-joins/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/azure-resource-graph-query-kql-joins/</guid>
      <description>Introduction A friend asked, How to pull resource groups tags, including resource information? Yes, it is the most common ask, and there are many ways to accomplish it! Time is precious, considering that let us skip the legacy methods like using the Az module, REST API, or SDK&amp;rsquo;s to query the Azure resources in the definitive loops. You are accountable for 200 + subscription and send a report of Azure resources in some schedules.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>